Prajot Pradeep Thorat

Senior Sales Specialist | BD | Assistant Sales Manager.

💌 prajot1902@gmail.com 📞 7039671227 💡 Mumbai, Maharashtra, India. 🛗 19/02/1993

Profile

As a driven and motivated Business Development Manager with over 6 years of experience, I have successfully collaborated with sales leaders and managed relationships to grow organizational revenue and increase brand value. In this role, I oversaw the development of several software projects, managing a team of 40-60 people. Being heavily involved in product testing and management, as well as identifying and developing new business opportunities that drove sales growth.

Skills

Communication

Convey ideas, information, and intentions effectively through verbal and written modes.

Financial Intelligence

Evaluate, analyze, and interpret financial data and use it to inform business decisions.

Information Technology

Interpret how information technology affects business operations and utilize business technologies to the advantage

Key account management.

Managing 10+ clients by collaborating with multiple teams.

Critical-Thinking / Negotiations.

Closing critical clients, while ensuring no loss of revenue and client satisfaction.

Business-to-Business commerce.

Experienced Account Manager with 3 years of expertise in driving B2B sales growth through strategic relationship building with key stakeholders.

Professional Experience

04/2023 - 07/2023 Mumbai, India

Business Development Manager

Spring Technologies

- Conducted extensive market research, identifying new business opportunities, growth areas, and strategic partnerships, contributing to 30% increase in lead acquisition.
- Proactively generated leads through targeted cold calling, successfully engaging key contacts within organizations.
- Built and nurtured strong client relationships, addressing their needs effectively and ensuring a 60% client satisfaction rate.
- Played a pivotal role in strategic planning and promotional activities, collaborating with the CEO to drive product visibility and market penetration.
- Demonstrated expertise in the CURD app's features, advising clients and internal teams for effective utilization.
- Engaged with 1000+ influencers within a 30-day period, significantly expanding app visibility and reach.
- Successfully collaborated with Rotary Club and Lions Club members in Mumbai, strengthening community networks.

• Conducted strategic meetings with BNI members across India, fostering partnerships and driving user engagement.

03/2021 – 01/2023 Mumbai, India

Senior Sales Specialist - Assistant Sales Manager.

AMPA orthodontics - Skinnsi

- Present and implement new strategies to increase financial growth while motivating the team.
- Complete hands-on experience with Salesforce.
- Conduct strategic meetings to ensure client satisfaction and report bugs in the current system, resulting in improved client satisfaction and brand image.
- Collaborate with multiple teams to craft solutions for smooth operations and revenue growth.
- Leading a team of 10+ associates to achieve set revenue targets every month.
- Completed total team revenue of 6 Cr in 1.8 years. Individually contributed to 78 Lakhs while motivating the team as well to excel in all segments.
- · Launched new upsell and cross-sell strategies
- Close critical cases excellently and gain client trust through a reference model, leading to revenue growth.
- Conduct personalized weekly sessions to work on strengths and drawbacks with associates.

12/2019 – 02/2021 Mumbai, India

Business Development Head

Nbytes Technologies private Ltd

- Researched and documented product features, revenue-generating sources and marketing opportunities.
- Led a team for competitor's businesses and benchmarking analysis. Conducting meetings with potential clients and presenting product features.
- Tools used for management Trello and Slack.
- Translated client feedback to the team, and brainstorm solutions for different segments of clients.
- Working on the core product to satisfy consumer pain points resulting in a smooth application flow. This included working on UX flow following the empathy track model and researching new modes to ease user communication.

03/2018 – 11/2019 Mumbai, India

Business development / Product lead

Biz technologies

- Assigned tasks to associates, staffed projects, tracked progress and updated managers, partners and clients as necessary.
- Collaborated with the sales team for generating sales for POS software. Scheduled meetings with potential clients and implemented product feedback accordingly.
- Leading a team of 40+ from different verticals like Website and mobile app development, design, marketing and sales.
- Managed multiple projects using Trello and Slack.
- Increased organizational business by 40% and client retention by 90%
- Accomplished a total revenue of 6 Cr during tenure and delivered over 40 successful projects while maintaining a loyal client base of 90%.
- Translate stakeholder requirements into over 10 different tangible deliverables such as functional specifications, user cases, user stories, workflow/process diagrams, and data flow/data model diagrams.

05/2017 – 02/2018 Mumbai, India

Project Manager.

- Market and competitor research in the competitive niche market.
- Improved the communication between the marketing and developing team.
- Researching potential leads from the open market, web and digital resources.
- To develop client relationships with a sense of trust and compassion.

Awards and Accolades.

Awarded Best team of the Month - Ampa Orthodontics Pvt Ltd - 2021

• Increased revenue by 30% while generating the highest revenue within 8 teams.

Top sales performer - Ampa Orthodontics Pvt Ltd - 2021

• Achieved record-breaking revenue by surpassing previous benchmarks

Best Product Manager - Biz Technologies Pvt Ltd - 2018

• Launched 3 new products in the Blockchain domain - Cryptocurrency Trading exchange, Explorer and ICO portals.

Education

Pune, India Bachelors of Engineering - Electronics and Telecommunication.

SKN - SITS Pune University